Guide to the Samuel R. Delany Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2017 acquisition, 200.17; (249 boxes) + 1 record album storage
  - Materials not processed on deposit, 1940-2017; 39.67; (70 boxes)
    - 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript draft fragments; 'The Jewel-Hinged Jaw', proof; "Chronology" of life of SRD, typescript; 'Hogg' Wikipedia entry printout, circa 2000s (Box 223)
    - Work by others including K. Leslie Steiner, photocopy and typescript; professional materials including student work; corrections; printed: "from Phallos"; writings by others regarding SRD; "Some Queer Notions About Race", typescript; typescript fragments by SRD; correspondence, circa 1970s-2010s (Box 224)
    - 'About Writing', bound draft; 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript draft fragment; paper scraps with holograph notes, circa 2000s (Box 225)
    - Printed journal: "The Writer's Chronicle", 2004 (Box 226)
    - Professional materials; 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript drafts; work and fragments by others; essay regarding 'The Mad Man' from "Unlimited Embrace", photocopy; pamphlets; letters; holograph notes; ephemera; printed comic books, 2000s-2010s (Box 227)
    - Typescript works by others; printed comic books; professional materials; work by other, photocopied fragment; 'In the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript draft; reviews of 'Dark Reflections', circa 2000s (Box 228)
    - 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', bound typescript drafts, 2007-2010 (Box 229)
    - 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript drafts; other writings relating to SRD, 2007 (Box 230)
    - Photocopied work by others; 'Dhalgren' corrections; professional materials; "The New Yorker", 1 copy; "The Gay & Lesbian Review", 4 copies; "The Lambda Book Report", 1 copy; online essays by others, printout, circa 2000-2003 (Box 231)
    - Professional materials, including student work; photocopied work by others; typescript fragments by SRD and K. Leslie Steiner, including 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders'; email correspondence; online printouts; printed: "Khatru 3 & 4", circa 1990s-2010s (Box 232)
    - 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript drafts and fragments; 'Hogg', bound proof; 'Phallos', bound typescript drafts; 'Dark Reflections', bound proof and typescript draft; reviews of works by SRD; "On Dark Reflections..." by Carl Freedman, typescript; email correspondence, circa 1995-2012 (Box 233)
    - 'Phallos', bound typescript draft; 'About Writing', draft; bound essays; essays by others, photocopies and proof; online printouts relating to philosophy; bound collections of writings relating to SRD, 2000s-2010s (Box 234)
    - Typescript drafts: "Notes on the Star Pit", 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', 'Dark Reflections', 'Phallos', 'About Writing', "The Prize"; 'The Mad Man', bound proofs; "The Gamble", photocopy; "Anatomy of a NOVA" and "Samuel R. Delany" fragment by K. Leslie Steiner, typescript drafts; photocopied and typescript work by others; promotional materials; professional materials, including student work; corrections for works by SRD; written piece and reviews relating to SRD; online printouts; correspondence, circa 1997-2010 (Box 235)
    - Photocopied work by others; email correspondence; 'About Writing', typescript draft; professional material: course packet, circa 2000s (Box 236)
    - Works by others, bound proof and photocopy; works by SRD, bound photocopy of typescripts; letter; 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript draft fragments; professional material: syllabus/course packet, circa 2000s (Box 237)
    - Typescript drafts and draft fragments: 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', 'Phallos', 'About Writing', short stories, essays, introduction; email correspondence; letters; corrections; typescript and photocopied works by others; flyers; online printouts; foreword regarding Joanna Russ, proof; professional materials, including student work, syllabi, meeting minutes and agendas, circa 1999-2010 (Box 238)
      - "Orpheus" album by various artists, 2005; 1 (Box 245)
    - 'Through the Valley of the Nest of Spiders', typescript draft; "Anatomy of a Nova" and "Samuel R. Delany" by K. Leslie Steiner, typescript drafts; "A Sheaf of Letters Concerning 'Night and the Loves of Joe Dicostanzo'", typescript draft; photocopied articles and reviews relating to SRD; photocopied work by others relating to SRD; 'Dark Matter' fragment, photocopy, 1997-2007, undated (Box 239)
    - Notebooks; email correspondence; ephemera; memorabilia; printed material relating Paul Williams; typescript drafts, pieces, and fragments; typescript work by others, including piece relating to SRD; professional materials, including syllabi; Facebook posts and chats, printout; Melville story, printout; letter with corrections for 'Phallos'; "The Atheist in the Attic", typescript draft; financial documents; legal documents; medical documents; correspondence; 'Dark Reflections', proof with holograph notes; conference schedule; book list; catalog including 'In Search of Silence'; scholarly article by others, printout; printed book: 'Science Fiction Analog Science Fact', including piece by SRD with holograph corrections, 1979-2016 (Box 240)
    - Printed World Trade Center memorial design; typescript pieces by SRD; legal documents; financial documents; medical documents; email correspondence; letter and letter fragments; Facebook posts, printout; book catalog including 'Phallos'; card; newspaper clippings; 'Flight From Neveryon', proof with holograph notes, 1985-2017 (Box 241)
    - Notebooks of Jean Mark Gawron; "A Guide to Interstellar Hitchhiking" by Jean Mark Gawron, typescript draft with holograph notes and corrections, circa 1970s (Box 242)
- September 2017 acquisition, circa 1960s-2013; 35; 28 boxes + 7 framed or flat art objects
  Gift of Samuel R. Delany, 2017
  Correspondence, writings, artwork, printed material, audiovisual material, awards, and other papers by or related to Samuel R. Delany
  In-process material. Research use may require advance notice. For further information, consult Access Services.